MATTHEW ALMANO

Software Engineer

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Cape Town South Africa

PHONE

0837037950

EMAIL

matthew.almano51@gmail.com

LINKS

Personal Portfolio

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

LEKR Product

SKILLS

Amazon AWS

Typescript

Node

React

Serverless

DevOps

MongoDB

Python

MySQL

PROFILE

Software Engineer with over 3 years of professional experience. I have taken ownership of multiple projects, from the initial client idea to the finished product released to the public. I am also in the process of releasing my own product.

My expertise lies primarily in backend development and DevOps, but I am currently working on shifting my focus towards frontend development.

In addition to my professional interests, I have a passion for a variety of activities outside of software engineering. I am an avid rock climber, and I also enjoy playing the guitar and exploring new hobbies. Currently, I am learning music production, and I am excited to continue to expand my skills in this area

I am open to a fully remote role within the UK and EU, as well as a partially remote role within Cape Town, South Africa.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Co Founder, LEKR SERVICES

Cape Town

May 2022 — Present

Created a product that provides business tools and business automation for small to medium businesses. The product can be viewed at lekr.co. The tech stack includes:

- · AWS Serverless lambda created in typescript
- · MongoDB integration
- · React Web App and React Native Mobile App

The product includes:

- · Custom Auth including OTP verification and token management
- · Quote and Invoice generation
- Lead generation

Alongside this, I was freelancing in my spare time.

Project Lead Software Engineer, MOHARA

Cape Town

Aug 2020 — Apr 2022

MOHARA is an international consultancy based in the UK with development hubs in South Africa and Thailand, I worked as a Full Stack engineer transitioning to project tech lead, across multiple projects, making use of a wide range of technologies denoted below.

I took ownership of multiple projects and saw them go from idea to successful product launch, whether it was only myself working on the product or being the tech lead and managing multiple software engineers.

Experience gained:

- Industry Experience in FinTech, HealthTech, PropertyTech, and IoT amongst others
- Full stack and managerial experience (Tech lead)
- · Front-end: React, Vue, React Native
- · Back-end: Typescript, Node, Python, Go, Ruby
- DevOps: AWS and Google Cloud Platform, Terraform, Serverless, Kubernetes, Docker
- · Solution Design and tier 0 scoping for new clients
- Business Development, interacting with current and potential new clients.
- · Working in team size from 0 15

Intern Software Engineer, SOLIDitech

Cape Town

Dec 2017 — Jan 2020

I was lucky enough to partake in the SOLIDitech internship programme during my university holidays throughout my university degree.

Throughout these internships I was able to achieve a lot of real world experience.

Notable experience gained includes:

- Leadership I was part of the leadership team that lead out an internal project within the business from the start of solution design to the end of the actual internal tool.
- Project Management Introduced and actively used the scrum process and agile framework
- Development Java based tech stack for FE(JSP) and BE development linked to a SQL database.

EDUCATION

BSc, Mathematical Sciences & Computer Science, University of Stellenbosch

Stellenbosch

Jan 2017 — Dec 2019